## ALI H. HAMMOUD

Ontario, Canada

#### SUMMARY

Results-driven Computer Engineer with over 15 years of experience offering cloud & networking solutions, fully committed to providing the highest possible standards of customer service and support. Strong work ethics, self-motivated, hard-working individual. Work well in challenging, fast-paced, high-stress and deadline-oriented environments individually or as part of a team. Troubleshooting is what I enjoy the most and learning new skills is my biggest passion.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Cloud Application Specialist – SHARCNET/SOSCIP at Western University London - ON, Canada ~ 05/2021 – Present

In this position, I provide technical leadership and support to identified SOSCIP research projects that make use of the SOSCIP cloud and GPU computing environments. I'm responsible for ensuring that the software environment within the cloud is operational and available to project teams, creating pre-defined software environments (virtual machines) for research projects and ensuring new software is installed in a timely fashion and tested for interoperability with other software components. I conduct a variety of engineering tasks related to the development, operation, and maintenance of complex technology systems, ensuring the integration of software, processes and methodologies to support the performance of the systems. In addition, I work closely with the SOSCIP Cloud administrators to ensure that virtual machines and containers used by project teams are reliable, efficient and maintained. I also provide advice and training on use of the cloud platform, and work closely with SOSCIP project research groups in use of the cloud and its software and applications.

# **Field Service Engineer – AV at Evertz Microsystems LTD.** Burlington - ON, Canada ~ 03/2017 – 05/2021

As an AV Field Engineer, I worked with the installation of Evertz network-based AV (audio/video) distribution solution products and systems at customer sites and delivering training to customers in-house or abroad. My daily tasks also included: providing technical direction to customers regarding operational issues, firmware upgrades and general maintenance, Assessing the customer's product application, troubleshoot and diagnosis issues through research and/or re-creation to determine the root cause. Systematic & detail-oriented troubleshooting, data collection and reporting while escalating issues. Recommending solutions utilizing various levels of technical language appropriate to the customer in a timely, clear and professional manner and maintaining a communication link between customer service and other departments by partnering to resolve customer issues and communicating customer feedback. I deployed and commissioned several AV over IP projects at customer sites including: Harvard University Business School (Boston, Massachusetts), Northwestern University Kellogg Business School (Chicago, Illinois), Oklahoma State University (Stillwater, OK), Nvidia Headquarters (Santa Clara, California), JP Morgan Chase Headquarters (Columbus, Ohio and NYC), Comcast Headquarters (Philadelphia, PA), Bank of America Headquarters (NYC), Morgan Stanley (Hong Kong) amongst others.

# Network & Solutions Engineer at Evertz Microsystems LTD. Burlington - ON, Canada $\sim 06/2016 - 03/2017$

In my role as a Network and Solutions Engineer at Evertz, I helped the Solutions team with the Implementation, documentation and deployment of both small and large scale IP Networks supporting broadcast infrastructures. My tasks also included responding and providing technical direction to customers regarding operational issues, firmware upgrades and general maintenance. Assessing the customer's application, troubleshoot and diagnose issues through research and/or re-creation to determine the root cause. Supporting the development of product communications by generating or authoring customer guides and provide the technical writing group with information including Printouts, FAQ, Application notes.

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

- 2022- AWS Certified SysOps Administrator Associate
  Validation Number 4T0EB5VCSJV4QQCH
- 2021- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals
  Certificate ID: 992132772
- 2021- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
  Validation Number V4M9LJPJL144Q2KG
- 2020- ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management
  Certificate Number: GR671170029AH
- 2013 & 2016 Cisco Certified Network Associate Security (CCNA Security) - ID: CSCO11867340
- 2010. Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) ID: CSCO11867340
- 2003-2009. **Computer Engineer**. Degree from the University Rafael Belloso Chacin. Maracaibo, Zulia State (Venezuela)

#### SKILLS

- Spoken and written Spanish, English & French.
- Audio-Visual experience deploying large scale projects and providing training to high-level customers.
- Advanced-level assembly, installation, repair and maintenance of computer equipment.
- Administration and installation of LAN and Wireless networks.
- Working experience with JavaScript, Ruby, HTML/CSS, Ticketing Systems, Office 365, OpenStack, as well as set up and administration of Linux servers (Red Hat & Ubuntu).

Supporting documents could be provided upon request.